# SUYA, FNU

85 Engineer's Way · Charlottesville · VA 22904 · (213) 590-6118 · fs5xz@virginia.edu

#### RESEARCH INTEREST

My main research interest is in machine learning security. Specifically, I am interested in evaluating robustness of machine learning models by designing better attack strategies. I am also interested in protecting data privacy in machine learning systems.

#### **EDUCATION**

2017-PRESENT · University of Virginia

PhD Computer Science · Department of Computer Science

GPA: 4.00/4.00

2015–2017 · Arizona State University

*PhD* Computer Science · School of Computing, Informatics, and Decision Systems Engineering GPA: 4.00/4.00

2010–2014 · Honors Program · China Agricultural University (CAU)

BE Electronic and Information Engineering track · College of Information and Electrical Engineering GPA: 3.65/4.00

## **AWARDS**

| 2018 | Computer Science | Graduate Research Award | University of Virginia |
|------|------------------|-------------------------|------------------------|
|      |                  |                         |                        |

2017 Computer Science Department Fellowship · University of Virginia

2016 NSF Travel Grant · GlobalSIP 2016

2015 CIDSE Doctoral Fellowship · Arizona State University

2011-2013 Excellent Student's Scholarship · China Agricultural University

#### ACADEMIC EXPERIENCE

### Research Assistant

01/2018-PRESENT · University of Virginia · Advisor: David Evans, Yuan Tian

- Designed hybrid black-box attack, which combines gradient and transfer black-box attacks, and improves upon state-of-the-art black-box attacks significantly in terms of attack success rate and query complexity.
- Studied the problem of improving query efficiency of hybrid attack in limited query setting and proposed efficient and effective seed prioritization strategies.

# Research Assistant

09/2017–11/2017 · University of Virginia · Advisor: David Evans, Yuan Tian

- Studied black-box attacks to machine learning classifiers with API access and applied Bayesian optimization to design black-box attack strategy with significantly improved query efficiency.

## Research Assistant

09/2016-05/2017 · ARIZONA STATE UNIVERSITY · Advisor: PAOLO PAPOTTI

 Worked on protecting user privacy in online platforms with query interaction. Applied Bayesian optimization strategy to modify user profiles (i.e., injecting carefully chosen noises) such that user profiles cannot be exactly identified by platform providers.

# Research Assistant

08/2015-05/2016 · Arizona State University · Advisor: Guoliang Xue

- Worked on designing truthful auction mechanism under sybil attack for radio spectrum allocation problem.
- Worked on designing robust wireless transmission strategy in the presence of malicious adversaries from a Stackelberg game perspective.

Research Intern 08/2014-02/2015 · Tsinghua University · Advisor: Wei Chen

- Studied power minimization problem for Cloud-RAN network with probabilistic Qualityof-Service constraints in the existence of imperfect channel state information (CSI). Proposed a power control algorithm to find solutions with optimality guarantees with reduced CSI signalling overhead.

Research Assistant 03/2013 - 10/2013 · China Agricultural University · Advisor: Minzan Li

- Developed Master-Slave mode of greenhouse group management system based on programmable logic controller (PLC) and ZigBee wireless sensor network.
- Developed remote control software for greenhouse monitoring system.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Conference

Fnu Suya, Jianfeng Chi, David Evans, Yuan Tian "Improved Estimation of Cost of Black-box Attacks" under review

Conference

Yi Chen, Mingming Zha, Nan Zhang, Dandan Xu, Qianqian Zhao, Xuan Feng, Kan Yuan, Fnu Suya, Yuan Tian, Kai Chen, XiaoFeng Wang, Wei Zou "Demystifying Hidden Privacy Settings in Mobile Apps" 40th IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (Oakland)

Poster

Fnu Suya, David Evans, Yuan Tian "Adversaries Dont Care About Averages: Batch Attacks on Black-Box Classifiers" 39th IEEE Symposium on Security and Privacy (Oakland)

Workshop

Fnu Suya, Yuan Tian, David Evans, Paolo Papotti "Qury-limited Black Box Attacks to Classifiers," NIPS Workshop on Machine Learning and Computer Security 2017

Conference

**Fnu Suya**, Yuanming Shi, Bo Bai, Wei Chen, Jun Zhang, Khaled B. Letaief, and Shidong Zhou "Optimal Stochastic Power Control with Compressive CSI Acquisition for Cloud-RAN," **IEEE Global Conference on Signal and Information Processing (GlobalSIP) 2016** 

Patent

Qin Lv, Fnu Suya, Youheng Fan. "A laser plane detection device for liquid viscosity coefficient measurement", CN 201310046368, filed Feb, 2013.

### TECHNICAL SKILLS

Programming

TensorFlow, PyTorch, Python, Matlab, C, C++

Language

Mongolian (Native), Chinese, English

## **COURSES**

CS6501 Natural Language Processing

CS6501 Learning Theory

CS 6161 Algorithms (UVa)

CSE 575 Statistical Machine Learning (ASU)

CSE 572 Data Mining (ASU)

CSE 691 (Topic) Advanced Topics in Social Media Analysis (ASU)

CSE 691 (Topic) Optimization with Engineering Applications

CSE 556 Game Theory (ASU)

CSE 539 Applied Cryptography (ASU)

CSE 100 Introduction to C++ Programming (ASU, TA)

CSE 240 Introduction to Programming Languages (ASU, TA)

CSE 556 Game Theory (ASU, TA)

# **SERVICES**

Journal Reviewer: China Communications' 16

External Reviewer: MobiHoc'16, SIGMOD'17, AAAI'17-19, DASFAA'17, NIPS'17, IEEE S&P'18-20,

ASIACCS'19